Amal Joy Chemparathy

Berlin, Germany amaljoyc@gmail.com

LINKS

GitHub

https://github.com/amaljoyc

LinkedIn

https://de.linkedin.com/in/amaljoyc

SKILLS

Expert

Java

Spring Core

Spring Cloud

Maven

Microservices

PostgreSQL

Linux / Bash

Prior Experience

Python

Django

Groovy

Jenkins

Docker

Chef

NodeJS

Kafka

Languages

English (Expert)
German (Basic)

Malayalam (Native)

SUMMARY

I'm a Software Engineer with 7+ years of professional experience in the design, architecture and development of many Software Applications. I have a strong passion for solving problems and building products and solutions through the application of technology.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2016-present TECHNICAL PRODUCT OWNER - smava GmbH

- ✓ I'm currently refactoring smava's Legacy Monolithic applications into Scalable Microservices.
- ✓ Started as a Backend Engineer and was involved in developing many Product Solutions for Marketing, CRM, Customer Facing App etc.
- ✓ Was later promoted to lead a team of 6 Backend Engineers. As a Team Lead, the main focuses were to make tech decisions, design and architect various software components, manage project and delivery, and hire new Engineers.

2015 - 2016 IT CONTRACTOR - Deutsche Telekom AG

- ✓ Lead the development / support of a 4 year old telecom project named HCS-RCS (configuring handsets to use Message+ Application).
- ✓ Worked closely with Product Owner following Agile / Scrum based development.

2013 – 2015 SYSTEMS ENGINEER – Infosys Ltd.

✓ Provided Software Services by performing end to end development like analysis, design and implementation of user stories including unit and integration testing.

2012 - 2013 INTERN PROGRAMMER - Aplopio Technology

✓ Involved in the development of the recruiting software - Recruiterbox (recruiterbox.com).

EDUCATION

2008 – 2012 Bachelor of Technology
Computer Science & Engineering
Cochin University